# 很多人来西宁
Most people are here in Xining
# 是为了打卡绝美的风景
For the breath-taking views
# 而雪鱼这次来西宁
But I’m here this time
# 不仅仅是来看风景 还有品尝大西北的美食
For not only the scenery, but also to taste the northwestern cuisines
# 从西安飞到西宁 一下飞机 我就觉得特别冷
I flew from Xi’an to Xining. And I felt so cold the moment I got off the plane
# 我发现我的手表上 出现了从来没有的数字显示
There appeared a new feature on my watch
# 我现在在海拔2千多米的高原上
that I’m now on an altitude more than 2000 meters
# 司机师傅告诉我们 在青海旅游就要注意两点
The driver told us there are two important things when you visit Qinghai
# 一个是防晒
One is sun screening
# 因为这边的紫外线特别强烈
Because the ultraviolet here is strong
# 第二个呢 一定要做好防雨的准备
And the other is rainproof
# 有的时候 之前可能是晴空万里
Sometimes the sky is clear and shiny
# 但是雨呢 就是说下就下
But the rain could fall any seconds
# 接下来雪鱼要去吃的是羊肠面 在当地是比较常见的
I’m going to have some lamb sausage noodles today, which is pretty popular here
# 名字听起来可能不太精致
It’s not an exquisite name
# 但是能够称得起当地特色的美食 味道应该不会很差
But it should taste well since it’s the local special
# 坐出租走吧
Let’s get a taxi
# 就是这家了，羊肠面
Here it is, lamb sausage noodles
# 你要啥样的
What can I get you?
# 一份羊肠面 再加一份牛头肉
A portion of lamb sausage noodles with an bowl of beef head meat
# 把牛头肉放在另一个碗里
The beef head meat in another bowl, please
# 看到周围一直注视的目光
Everybody was staring at me
# 我意识到我可能答非所问
I realized I was not answering to what had been asked
# 通过不断的比划和重复 我想要的是
I had to make gesture repeatedly to let them understand what I wanted were
# 一碗羊肠面和一份牛头肉
An order of lamb sausage noodles with an order of beef head meat
# 这种摊在桌子上的
These thin noodles on the table
# 要不断用手抓 不断散落的
that are grabbed constantly and scattering all around
# 金黄色的细面条
with a golden yellow colour
# 是用鸡蛋 面粉和食用碱做成的
are made with eggs, flour and soda ash
# 把它煮到七八分熟后 捞出来过凉水
Boil them until medium well and cool them in water
# 处理好的面条 就会放在店里最显眼的位置
The noodles are then put at the most obvious place once ready
# 客人点完面 就把面放在沸汤里过几遍
When ordered, the noodles will be blanched a few times in the boiling soup
# 大约几秒就可以出锅
It will take just a few seconds
# 如果面上码了肉
If you order noodles with meat
# 肉呢 也会随面一起进入漏勺
The meat will be in the slotted spoon with the noodles
# 经历几次漏勺开花 最后一同进入碗中
Blanching a few times and put it in the bowl together
# 现在是调上醋 蒜 辣子 我们就可以端走了
Now they are putting some vinegar, garlic sauce and chili oil in there and it will be ready
# 今天吃的就是羊肠面
Today we have the lamb sausage noodles
# 除了面以外，我们还要了一份牛头肉 共消费22元
Besides the noodles, we ordered some beef head meat too. It costs 22 yuan in total
# 这碗是免费自己盛的汤
This is the free soup
# 羊肠面 看字面意思就是羊肠加面
Lamb sausage noodles. As the name implies, it’s noodle with lamb sausages
# 面是提前用个鸡蛋 面粉 食用碱一起和出来的
The noodles were made of eggs, flour and soda ash
# 你看 这边的抓面 一根都有1米长
The noodles here are at least one meter long
# 最长的能够达到3米
The longest can be 3 meters
# 每抓一次面都是在做力气活啊
It’s like working out every time they grab them
# 这么一挑面条 冒着热气
The steam comes out when we pick up the noodles
# 我们尝一尝吧
Let’s give it a try
# 这个面条很像武汉的热干面
The noodles are pretty similar to the Wuhan’s hot dry noodles
# 是干拌的 看起来又很筋道
The noodles seem al dente and the dressing is dry
# 面条里加了辣子是很香的
The chili oil in the noodles smells so good
# 没有一点的汤汁
No soup in there at all
# 面条之间主要靠表面的油来分离开
The noodles are separated by the oil on the surface
# 来尝尝今天的主角 羊肠
Let’s try today’s special, the lamb sausages
# 羊肠不是空心的 分肉肠和面肠的
The lamb sausages have meat sausages and dough sausages
# 像这种颜色比较深的
These sausages are darker in color
# 里面就是用羊的内脏加调料做出来的
The ingredients are lamb offal with seasoning
# 而这个颜色比较浅的
These sausages are lighter in color
# 就是用豆面糊加调料煮出来的
It’s made of bean flour and seasonings
# 吃面肠就像吃山药一样，面面的口感
The dough sausages have a grainy texture like Chinese yam
# 外面的肠衣是脆的 里面是绵的
The sausage casing is crunchy and the inside is delicate
# 面肠的味道会比较淡一些
The dough sausages taste lighter
# 肉肠的味道就是胡椒粉的辛辣味道比较重
The meat sausages have a strong taste of pepper
# 一碗面里的羊肠不多
There’s not many lamb sausages in one order of noodles
# 已经被我默默地吃掉四五个了
And I’ve already had four or five of them
# 肉肠挂辣子 吃起来更香 更辣
The sausages with the chili oil taste more spicy and delicious
# 会吃肠子的人 都知道
Those who enjoy sausages would know
# 像羊肠这种东西 就是把内壁洗干净
To make lamb sausages, first we need to clean its internal surface
# 但是一定不要刮这个肠壁油
But leave the intestine fat on there
# 因为有肠壁油 羊肠吃起来才会更香
It’s the fat that makes the sausages more aromatic
# 总的来说 清洗羊肠 就是要洗的干净
In general, we need to make the intestines clean
# 但是不能洗的太过于干净
But not too clean
# 这样的分寸要拿捏好
Need to be careful with that
# 很多人听到羊肠面这个名字 听起来是很重口的
The name lamb sausage noodles sounds pretty intimidatinf
# 所以说内心会比较排斥
Some people may be refused to try it
# 但是试一试你会发现
But after trying you’ll find out
# 它并没有想象的那么黑暗难吃
It’s not too heavy or nasty as you may have imagined
# 辣子 肉香 面香啊 让你越吃越想吃
You can never have enough of the aroma of chili oil, meat and the noodles
# 这是个炉子 是用来加热酸汤的
This is a stove to heat up the soup
# 但它不仅仅是一个炉子 还是一个桌子
It’s also a table
# 很多人就是围着炉子一边吃面一边喝汤
Many people sit around this stove to have noodles and soup at the same time
# 我们的西宁美食之旅从这期就要开始啦
Our food tasting journey of Xining starts from this episode